Egle Strockyte

Product Design Manager

egle.strockyte@gmail.com 1 (323) 504-1778 | egle.design

PROFILE

I am a product design manager who enjoys guiding my team through focused work that lead to both customer and business results.

I have 9+ years of in-house and agency-side experience.
Besides enjoying my current ride at Bird, I have previously worked with clients such as The Economist, McKinsey & Company, City of Santa Monica and Faraday Future.

SKILLS

People Management
UX Design and Strategy
Product Design
User Research & Testing
Information Architecture
Wireframing
Content Modeling
UI Design
Creative Concept Development
Typography
HTML & CSS

EDUCATION

Master of Arts, Publishing (2010) University of the Arts London, LCC

Bachelor of Arts, Journalism and Media & Culture Studies (2009) Kingston University, London

Fine Arts Diploma (2005) Siauliai Art School, Lithuania

EXPERIENCE

Senior Product Design Manager, Bird

2019 June-present

I currently work at electric scooter company Bird where I lead a team focused on designing meaningful experiences for our riders and fleet managers.

UX Design Director, Edenspiekermann

2016-2019

I designed digital products and experiences for brands in automotive, technology, government, publishing and finance. In my position as a UX Design Director, I owned and guided my team's design processes, methodologies and activities from concept through to finished product. I enjoyed coaching my team through challenges as much as being a hands-on member of the team at all stages of the project.

Product Designer, The Economist

2015-2016

I helped to create the new digital home of The Economist.
I meaningfully participated in the publication's new website ideating, prototyping, and development process, working with a large globally distributed stakeholders team.
Besides working on economist.com redesign, I was also a principle designer on the project code named CASE.
Throughout this project, I helped to reimagine The Economist's e-commerce journey by redesigning dashboard from which a logged-in user could manage their subscriptions, bookmarks and comments.

Designer, Global Trade Review (GTR)

2012-2015

I planned and led GTR's digital rebrand. Designed and shipped the new responsive company's website alongside the email newsletters and confirmation emails. I played key role in liaison with numerous teams including web developers, editorial and marketing.

Freelance Designer

2011-2012

Worked on various web and print design projects for different clients. Design work mainly included responsive website mock-ups, client reports and presentations, posters and, also, physical product design.